Wilton Historical Society Neighborhoods and Old Houses Collection
Wilton History Room, Wilton Historical Society
- 1. Houses
  - Houses by address and name
    - 128 Westport Road - Jayne Brothers, gravel mine and crusher, undated; Built 1920. (Cabinet 2, Folder 1452)
    - 44 Westport Road - Lilacstead slave house, undated; Built circa 1759. (Cabinet 2, Folder 1450)
    - 308 Westport Road - Raymond barn, undated; Built circa 1900. (Cabinet 2, Folder 1472)
    - 306 Westport Road - Reuben Stuart house, undated; Built circa 1748. (Cabinet 2, Folder 1470)
    - 190 Westport Road - Stiles Green house, undated; Built 1833. (Cabinet 2, Folder 1462)
    - 301 Westport Road - Waterbury house, undated; Built circa 1820. (Cabinet 2, Folder 1468)
    - 183 Westport Road - Weitz house, undated; Built circa 1935. (Cabinet 2, Folder 1460)
    - 132 Westport Road - Zackariah Fitch house, undated; Built 1800. (Cabinet 2, Folder 1454)
    - 155 Whipstick Road - Betts house, undated; Built circa 1870. (Cabinet 2, Folder 1474)
    - 2 Wilton Acres - Eliphalet Morehouse house, undated; Built before 1853. (Cabinet 2, Folder 1476)
    - 10 Wilton Acres - Samuel P. Randle house, undated; Built circa 1800. Formerly 84 Danbury Road. (Cabinet 2, Folder 1480)
    - 19 Windy Ridge Place, undated (Cabinet 2, Folder 1485)
    - 201 Wolfpit Road, undated (Cabinet 2, Folder 1492)
    - 31 Wolfpit Road - Thaddeus Betts house, "Arnold Farm", undated; Built circa 1754. (Cabinet 2, Folder 1490)
    - 9 Woodway Lane - Dibner house, undated; Built circa 1929. (Cabinet 2, Folder 1500)
  - Miscellaneous
    - “Homes for Living”, 1974; Real Estate Brochure (Cabinet 2, Folder 122)
    - House genealogy - Card file, undated; Alphabetic by last name of owners of Wilton 18th century homes. Includes name of original owner and subsequent owners with dates. (Cabinet 27, Folder 4-4)
    - Old house portraits, undated (Cabinet 2, Folder 425)
    - Old houses of Wilton, 1964; Includes a map by Robert Carboni. (Cabinet 2, Folder 435)
    - Steel houses in Wilton, undated (Cabinet 2, Folder 1415)
    - Neighborhood histories, undated; Wilton history as written by Troy and Zoe Resch of the Wilton Singers for the Bicentennial Feast. (Cabinet 2, Folder 275)
- 2. Surveys, censuses, and research
  - Old house architectural survey, 1978-1980
    - List of homes surveyed, 1978-1980; See also books. (Cabinet 2, Folder 375)
  - Old house architectural survey, 1989
    - Correspondence, 1989 (Cabinet 2, Folder 390)
    - Homes rejected for 1989 survey (Cabinet 2, Folder 388)
    - House forms, 1989 (Cabinet 2, Folder 386)
    - List of homes surveyed, 1989 (Cabinet 2, Folder 385)
    - Miscellaneous notes, 1989 (Cabinet 2, Folder 391)
    - Office of the State Historic Preservation Officer, undated (Cabinet 2, Folder 392)
    - Volunteer information, 1989 (Cabinet 2, Folder 389)
    - Windshield survey lists, 1989 (Cabinet 2, Folder 387)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Century Census: Homes before 1845, 1946 (Cabinet 2, Folder 110)
  - Old house census - Bicentennial project
    - Book publication, 1975 (Cabinet 2, Folder 408)
    - Correspondence, 1975 (Cabinet 2, Folder 405)
    - Notes and lists, 1975 (Cabinet 2, Folder 400)
  - Old house research
    - Instructions, undated (Cabinet 2, Folder 410)
    - Notes, undated (Cabinet 2, Folder 420)
- 3. Neighborhoods
  - Miscellaneous
    - Commonage, 1739 (Cabinet 2, Folder 120)
    - Location names, undated (Cabinet 2, Folder 125)
  - Neighborhoods by name
    - Bald Hill, undated; Includes Hop Meadow, Keeler's Ridge, Ridgefield Road, and Rockhouse. (Cabinet 2, Folder 130)
    - Belden Hill, undated; Includes Horse Pound and Sear Hill. (Cabinet 2, Folder 140)
    - Cannondale, undated; Includes Captain's Plain, Cole's Fallow, Copps Farm, Dumplin Hill, Egypt, Harrie's Ridge, Honey Hill, Lee's Brook, Scribner Hill, Sturges Ridge, and Wampum Hill. (Cabinet 2, Folder 150)
    - Chestnut Hill, undated; Includes Chestnut Hill Properties, Great Swamp, Indian Field, Skunk Hole, and Westport Road. (Cabinet 2, Folder 160)
    - Chicken Street, undated (Cabinet 2, Folder 165)
    - Comstock Ridge, undated (Cabinet 2, Folder 170)
    - Cottage Row, undated (Cabinet 2, Folder 180)
    - Danbury and School Roads - Harbs property, undated; Tentative history of the house on the Harbs property: possibly built circa 1728 by Stephen Betts. (Cabinet 2, Folder 185)
    - Danbury Road, undated (Cabinet 2, Folder 183)
    - Drum Hill, undated (Cabinet 2, Folder 190)
    - Dumplin Hill, 1877 (Cabinet 2, Folder 195)
    - Georgetown, undated; See also WHI, Georgetown, Register of Historic Places. (Cabinet 2, Folder 200)
    - Glen Hill, undated (Cabinet 2, Folder 205)
    - Hurlbutt Street, undated; Includes Buckingham Ridge, Harrie's Ridge, and Sturges Ridge. (Cabinet 2, Folder 210)
    - Kent, undated; Includes South Wilton and Wolfboro. (Cabinet 2, Folder 220)
    - Nod Hill, undated; Includes Chicken Street, Ketchum's Bog, Millstone, and Rockhouse. (Cabinet 2, Folder 230)
    - Nod Hill Parade - Video, 2009-2011; Fourth of July parades, 2009, 2010, and 2011. (Cabinet 2, Folder 231)
    - Olmstead Hill, undated; Includes Round Hill and Salt Pound. (Cabinet 2, Folder 240)
    - Pimpewaug, undated; Includes Danbury Road, Mill Road, Prink's Plain, Sharp Hill, Skunk Lane, Split Rock Farm, Stephen's Swamp, and Toilsome Hill. (Cabinet 2, Folder 250)
    - Ridgefield Road, undated (Cabinet 2, Folder 260)
    - Wilton Center, undated (Cabinet 2, Folder 270)
  - Neighborhoods prior to 1802
    - Block 1 - Old Belden Hill, Seir Hill, undated; Research compiled by Malcolm Hunt of Lockwood House Museum, Norwalk, Conn. Refer to map. See also Map Tube #11. (Cabinet 2, Folder 280)
    - Block 10 - Danbury Road, Dudley Road, Chestnut Hill, Grumman Hill, Westport Road, undated; Three files (Parts 1-3) of research compiled by Malcolm Hunt of Lockwood House Museum, Norwalk, Conn. Refer to map. See also Map Tube #11. (Cabinet 2, Folder 296, 298, 300)
    - Block 11 - Dudley Road, Chestnut Hill, Westport Road, undated; Two files (Parts 1-2) of research compiled by Malcolm Hunt of Lockwood House Museum, Norwalk, Conn. Refer to map. See also Map Tube #11. (Cabinet 2, Folder 301, 302)
    - Block 12 - Belden Hill, Cheese Spring, Drum Hill, Seir Hill, undated; Two files (Parts 1-2) of research compiled by Malcolm Hunt of Lockwood House Museum, Norwalk, Conn. Refer to map. See also Map Tube #11. (Cabinet 2, Folder 303, 304)
    - Block 12A, undated; Research compiled by Malcolm Hunt of Lockwood House Museum, Norwalk, Conn. Refer to map. See also Map Tube #11. (Cabinet 2, Folder 305)
    - Block 13 - Danbury Road, Drum Hill, Belden Hill, Old Ridgefield Road, Wolfpit Road, undated; Four files (Parts 1-4) of research compiled by Malcolm Hunt of Lockwood House Museum, Norwalk, Conn. Refer to map. See also Map Tube #11. (Cabinet 2, Folder 306, 307, 309, 310)
    - Block 13, Part 5 - Prinks Plain, undated; Research compiled by Malcolm Hunt of Lockwood House Museum, Norwalk, Conn. Refer to map. See also Map Tube #11. (Cabinet 2, Folder 311)
    - Block 13, Part 6 - Wilton Center, undated; Research compiled by Malcolm Hunt of Lockwood House Museum, Norwalk, Conn. Refer to map. See also Map Tube #11. (Cabinet 2, Folder 312)
    - Block 14 - Cherry Lane, Danbury Road, Dudley Road, Sharp Hill, undated; Research compiled by Malcolm Hunt of Lockwood House Museum, Norwalk, Conn. Refer to map. See also Map Tube #11. (Cabinet 2, Folder 314)
    - Block 15 - Cherry Lane, Chestnut Hill, Dudley Road, Shadow Lane, undated; Research compiled by Malcolm Hunt of Lockwood House Museum, Norwalk, Conn. Refer to map. See also Map Tube #11. (Cabinet 2, Folder 316)
    - Block 16 - Danbury Road, Old Highway, Sharp Hill, undated; Three files (Parts 1-3) of research compiled by Malcolm Hunt of Lockwood House Museum, Norwalk, Conn. Refer to map. See also Map Tube #11. (Cabinet 2, Folder 318, 320, 322)
    - Block 17 - Cherry Lane, Hurlbutt Street, Sharp Hill, Shadow Lane, undated; Research compiled by Malcolm Hunt of Lockwood House Museum, Norwalk, Conn. Refer to map. See also Map Tube #11. (Cabinet 2, Folder 323)
    - Block 18 - Liberty Street, Sturges Ridge Road, undated; Two files (Parts 1-2) of research compiled by Malcolm Hunt of Lockwood House Museum, Norwalk, Conn. Refer to map. See also Map Tube #11. (Cabinet 2, Folder 324, 326)
    - Block 19 - Cedar Road, Chestnut Hill, Westport Road, undated; Research compiled by Malcolm Hunt of Lockwood House Museum, Norwalk, Conn. Refer to map. See also Map Tube #11. (Cabinet 2, Folder 328)
    - Block 2 - Danbury Road, Grist Mill Road, Kent Road, Old Belden Hill, undated; Research compiled by Malcolm Hunt of Lockwood House Museum, Norwalk, Conn. Refer to map. See also Map Tube #11. (Cabinet 2, Folder 282)
    - Block 20 - Chestnut Hill, Westport Road, undated; Research compiled by Malcolm Hunt of Lockwood House Museum, Norwalk, Conn. Refer to map. See also Map Tube #11. (Cabinet 2, Folder 329)
    - Block 21 - Belden Hill, Drum Hill, Ridgefield Road, undated; Two files (Parts 1-2) of research compiled by Malcolm Hunt of Lockwood House Museum, Norwalk, Conn. Refer to map. See also Map Tube #11. (Cabinet 2, Folder 330, 332)
    - Block 22 - Danbury Road, Lovers Lane, Ridgefield Road, undated; Research compiled by Malcolm Hunt of Lockwood House Museum, Norwalk, Conn. Refer to map. See also Map Tube #11. (Cabinet 2, Folder 334)
    - Block 23 - Danbury Road, Hurlbutt Street, Old Highway, Pimpewaug Road, Sharp Hill, Skunk Lane, undated; Two files (Parts 1-2) of research compiled by Malcolm Hunt of Lockwood House Museum, Norwalk, Conn. Refer to map. See also Map Tube #11. (Cabinet 2, Folder 336, 338)
    - Block 24 - Cannon Road, Hurlbutt Street, Liberty Street, Sturges Ridge Road, undated; Two files (Parts 1-2) of research compiled by Malcolm Hunt of Lockwood House Museum, Norwalk, Conn. Refer to map. See also Map Tube #11. (Cabinet 2, Folder 340, 342)
    - Block 25 - Danbury Road, Lovers Lane, Pimpewaug Road, Ridgefield Road, undated; Three files (Parts 1-3) of research compiled by Malcolm Hunt of Lockwood House Museum, Norwalk, Conn. Refer to map. See also Map Tube #11. (Cabinet 2, Folder 344, 346, 348)
    - Block 26 - Cannon Road, Danbury Road, Pimpewaug Road, undated; Two files (Parts 1-2) of research compiled by Malcolm Hunt of Lockwood House Museum, Norwalk, Conn. Refer to map. See also Map Tube #11. (Cabinet 2, Folder 350, 352)
    - Block 27 - Cannon Road, Hurlbutt Street, Pimpewaug Road, Skunk Lane, undated; Two files (Parts 1-2) of research compiled by Malcolm Hunt of Lockwood House Museum, Norwalk, Conn. Refer to map. See also Map Tube #11. (Cabinet 2, Folder 354, 356)
    - Block 28 - Cedar Lane, Sturges Ridge, undated; Research compiled by Malcolm Hunt of Lockwood House Museum, Norwalk, Conn. Refer to map. See also Map Tube #11. (Cabinet 2, Folder 358)
    - Block 3 - Danbury Road, Grumman Avenue, Kensett Road, undated; Research compiled by Malcolm Hunt of Lockwood House Museum, Norwalk, Conn. Refer to map. See also Map Tube #11. (Cabinet 2, Folder 284)
    - Block 30 - DeForest Road, Millstone Road, Nod Hill Road, Olmstead Hill, Ridgefield Road, undated; Research compiled by Malcolm Hunt of Lockwood House Museum, Norwalk, Conn. Refer to map. See also Map Tube #11. (Cabinet 2, Folder 360)
    - Block 32 - Chicken Street, Danbury Road, Olmstead Hill, Scribner Hill, undated; Two files (Parts 1-2) of research compiled by Malcolm Hunt of Lockwood House Museum, Norwalk, Conn. Refer to map. See also Map Tube #11. (Cabinet 2, Folder 362, 364)
    - Block 33 - Cannon Road, Danbury Road, Seeley Road, undated; Research compiled by Malcolm Hunt of Lockwood House Museum, Norwalk, Conn. Refer to map. See also Map Tube #11. (Cabinet 2, Folder 366)
    - Block 37, undated; Research compiled by Malcolm Hunt of Lockwood House Museum, Norwalk, Conn. Refer to map. See also Map Tube #11. (Cabinet 2, Folder 368)
    - Block 38, undated; Research compiled by Malcolm Hunt of Lockwood House Museum, Norwalk, Conn. Refer to map. See also Map Tube #11. (Cabinet 2, Folder 370)
    - Block 6 - Belden Hill, Old Range Road, Wolfpit Road, undated; Research compiled by Malcolm Hunt of Lockwood House Museum, Norwalk, Conn. Refer to map. See also Map Tube #11. (Cabinet 2, Folder 286)
    - Block 7, Part 1 - Danbury Road, Kent Road, Old Belden Hill, Old Range Road, Wolfpit Road, undated; Research compiled by Malcolm Hunt of Lockwood House Museum, Norwalk, Conn. Refer to map. See also Map Tube #11. (Cabinet 2, Folder 288)
    - Block 7, Part 2 - Danbury Road, Kent Road, undated; Research compiled by Malcolm Hunt of Lockwood House Museum, Norwalk, Conn. Refer to map. See also Map Tube #11. (Cabinet 2, Folder 290)
    - Block 7, Part 3 - Old Range Road, Wolfpit Road, undated; Research compiled by Malcolm Hunt of Lockwood House Museum, Norwalk, Conn. Refer to map. See also Map Tube #11. (Cabinet 2, Folder 292)
    - Block 8 - Danbury Road, Grumman Avenue, Grumman Hill, Kensett Avenue, undated; Research compiled by Malcolm Hunt of Lockwood House Museum, Norwalk, Conn. Refer to map. See also Map Tube #11. (Cabinet 2, Folder 294)
- 4. Roads, road names, and trails
  - Cannon Road - Comments by Stowell Rounds, 1955 (Cabinet 2, Folder 105)
  - Chicken Street, undated (Cabinet 2, Folder 1570)
  - General information, undated (Cabinet 2, Folder 1550)
  - Hubbard Road, 1987 (Cabinet 2, Folder 1560)
  - Kensett, undated (Cabinet 2, Folder 1620)
  - Partrick Lane, undated (Cabinet 2, Folder 1580)
  - Pimpewaug, undated (Cabinet 2, Folder 1590)
  - Road names, undated; See also booklet by Stowell Rounds, “A Connecticut Town names its Roads.” See also Wilton Roads by John Sturges, 974.69. (Cabinet 2, Folder 263)
  - Rockhouse Woods, undated (Cabinet 2, Folder 1600)
  - Scribner, undated (Cabinet 2, Folder 1610)
  - Southern connector road study, undated (Cabinet 2, Folder 265)
  - Wolfpit Road through Horseshoe Road, undated (Cabinet 2, Folder 271)
  - Ridgefield Road overpass - Correspondence, 1937-1938 (Cabinet 2, Folder 1085)
  - Bicycle trail - History, 1975 (Cabinet 2, Folder 100)